Shubhangi Agarwal

shubhangiat.github.io | in shubhangi-agarwal

+91-512-259-7579
sagarwal@cse.iitk.ac.in

SUMMARY

I am a researcher with a background in **Graph Mining** and **Machine Learning**. I have developed various algorithms based on statistical analysis for **Subgraph Querying** in large complex graphs. Some of the many areas that can benefit from the querying of subgraph structures are **information extraction**, **recommendation systems**, **disease diagnostics**, **fraud detection** are. I am intersted in developing effective and efficient algorithms for analyzing complex data structures using state-of-the-art machine learning techniques.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh, India

Bachelor of Technology Computer Engineering

Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology, Surat, Gujarat, India

CGPA: 8.25 2014 - current

......

CGPA: 8.71 2010 - 2014

Supervisor: Arnab Bhattacharya

PHD THESIS

Subgraph Matching and Mining in Large Graphs

• Developed algorithms for Approximate Subgraph Matching in both deterministic and probabilistic graphs.

• Proposed a Graph Neural Network model for robust node embeddings with positional information.

PUBLICATIONS

- "VeNoM: Approximate Subgraph Matching with Enhanced Neighbourhood Structural Information", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, 7th Joint International Conference on Data Science and Management of Data (CODS-COMAD), 2024, India.
- "VerSaChI: Finding Statistically Significant Subgraph Matches using Chebyshev's Inequality", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2021, pages 2812-2816, Australia.
- "GraphReach: Position-Aware Graph Neural Network using Reachability Estimations", Sunil Nishad, **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Arnab Bhattacharya and Sayan Ranu, Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2021, pages 1527-1533, Canada.
- "ChiSeL: Graph Similarity Search using Chi-Squared Statistics in Large Probabilistic Graphs", **Shubhangi Agarwal**, Sourav Dutta and Arnab Bhattacharya, Proceedings of the International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), 2020, pages 1654-1668, Japan.

EXPERIENCES

External Reviewer 2020 - current

• WSDM (2024), CIKM (2021, 2022), DASFAA (2022), CoDS-COMAD (2020, 2021), KDD (2021)

Teaching Assistant (IIT Kanpur)

Aug 2014 - Apr 2021

• Graded and evaluated projects for various courses of Computer Science.

Senior Tutor (IIT Kanpur)

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018, Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

• Led teams of strength \sim 60; Assisted in backend management, paper-setting and grading.

Teaching Assistant for MOOC (NPTEL - Remote)

July 2017 - Sep 2017

Crafted objective questions and resolved student queries on Fundamentals of Database Systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : C, C++, Java, Python, R, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, Shell scripting

Libraries : PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas

Tools : git, LaTeX, Docker, Weka

REFERENCES

Arnab Bhattacharya

Professor, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur

★ https://cse.iitk.ac.in/users/arnabb/

Souray Dutta

Chief NLP Research Scientist, Huawei Research Centre

★ https://sites.google.com/view/homesouravdutta/

arnabb@iitk.ac.in, arnabb@iitk.ac.in

**** +91-512-259-7650

Sourav.dutta2@huawei.com